Torso Twist with Buddha Arms and elbows extended.
No meditation just a fancy name to give you a visual of what the arms are going to do.
But the torso twist is a great way to train your middle, the middle of your body.
Start training your obliques and same with the back and the middle area.
So when you when your stance just like I am right now.
You want your feet about shoulder width, toes slightly out.
When you bend your knees make sure that you keep your hips underneath the shoulders that they're not pushed forward like this.
So check in the mirror, make sure that you're not ahead out of alignment. You're going to tuck your hips and that's what's tricky is tucking this way so you feel like almost like somebody's pulling you from the front of the pants or you're looking at a caught zipper or something here and that's what you do when you do that.
So keeping that, bringing the belly in by getting that vacuum in and shoulders down.
Now the arms are going to go in front of you.
The hands in front of the chest and the elbows out.
You're going to press into the hands like you're fighting.
Like you're having a match here with the hands that's going to keep nice tension all throughout the upper body.
As you twist keep the hands in front don't let them go ahead.
That's a very common thing to do when you're not familiar with the exercise.
Keeping the hips facing forward if you notice my belly button is still facing the same way as I'm twisting.
Play with the breathing inhale, exhale.
Now instead of looking down, I'm looking at my hands right now to make sure you want to do that but also keep the gaze forward.
So you want to make sure that you keep the hands in front, maybe kind of look at them without lowering your chin.
Do a few of these and before you know it you're going to have a nice strong core.
Nice middle section and same with the back and it's going to make a difference in the way you feel and the way you look so good luck to you.